Lucas Pinto

São Paulo, Brazil



lucas.henrique223@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/lucashenriquepinto

Summary

A geek, passionate about my work, friendly and with the super power of tech leadership and fast learning with extensive experience on many IT fields, with most interest on tech leadership and senior positions using Javascript (vanilla and/or frameworks, Node, React, Next, Apollo etc) and GraphQL API.

Currently working for Paramount as an Engineering Lead and leading a team of 14+ people in a huge project for a fortune 100 company.

Past highlights includes receiving in San Francisco an Engineering Emmy Award in 2020 for Evercast, a project that I've built from scratch 100% remotely, and founding two startups.

Specialities: Senior Leadership, Tech Leadership, Javascript (React, Relay, GraphQL, NodeJS, Next, Nest, Apollo, +) SQL databases, Linux Systems, GraphQL, Python, MEAN stack, Devops (Terraform, cloud systems) and more.

Experience

ct Senior Full-Stack Developer / Tech Lead

Clevertech

Sep 2015 - Present (6 years 6 months +)

Currently working as a Senior Engineering Lead for a Fortune 100 26 billion-dollar worth company that is the leader in the TV industry. Details of the project is under NDA.

Previous projects:

- Led a project for 5 years from start to finish, which is generating millions of dollars in revenue monthly right now -- and we also won an Engineering Emmy Award in 2020 due to how impactful the product has been for the movie industry. Users includes Apple, Paramount, Disney, Sony, Marvel, and other giants in the movie-industry.
- Worked as a senior front-end developer using EmberJS to support the development of a huge application used by the top model agencies companies worldwide.

Founder

Lupyx Solutions

Jun 2015 - Present (6 years 9 months +)

OSF Senior Full-Stack Developer

OSF Digital

Feb 2015 - Sep 2015 (8 months)

Working for Hyatt Hotels Corporation, built an entire application used to manage the construction of the Hyatt Hotels all over the globe, which is still being used as of 2022.

Tech used: Microsoft Sharepoint, Javascript, SQL Server, C#.

SecrelNet Full-Stack Developer

Secrelnet Informática Ltda.

Jul 2011 - Feb 2015 (3 years 8 months)

- Team leader of a team of developers in a project using Openstack to build an Cloud Solution (like AWS)
- Created a call center monitoring painel connected to an Asterisk server using NodeJS + jQuery.
- Created hybrid mobile applications using Titanium framework
- Created and worked on integration systems using .NET that manages the servers and hosting solutions
- Built an applet in Java that managed contracts and legal stuff for accounting offices.

Techs worked: Javascript (NodeJS, jQuery, AngularJS, EmberJS), Python, .NET (VB and C#), Mono Framework (C# on Unix), Asterisk, Java, SQL Server, Mysql, PHP.

DevOps Engineer

GXS

Apr 2010 - Jun 2011 (1 year 3 months)

Education



Universidade de Fortaleza

Ciencia da computação, Computer Science 2011 - 2016

Licenses & Certifications



Oracle Certified Java Programmer 7 - Oracle

Issued Dec 2013 - Expires Dec 2018



Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 7 Programmer - Oracle

Skills

JavaScript • React.js • Node.js • Microsoft .NET • SQL • Python • C++ • UML • PHP • C#

Honors & Awards



Emmy Engineering Award 2020 - Emmy - ACADEMY OF TELEVISION ARTS & **SCIENCES**

Dec 2020

Evercast, the project I had worked for over 5 years as a senior lead developer won an international engineering emmy award due to it's relevance and how the movie industry was able to keep shooting blockbusters movies even during pandemic times, saving literally thousands of jobs while allowing everyone around the world to continue to watch new amazing movies and tv series.

https://www.emmys.com/news/awards-news/engineering-201008